Witness the origin.
Transformers One is a animation, science fiction,
adventure film directed by Josh Cooley.
The untold origin story of Optimus Prime and Megatron, better known as sworn enemies, but once
were friends bonded like brothers who changed the fate of Cybertron forever.
Orion Pax / Optimus Prime (voice), played by Chris Hemsworth.
D-16 / Megatron (voice), played by Brian Tyree Henry.
Elita-1 (voice), played by Scarlett Johansson.
B-127 (voice), played by Keegan-Michael Key.
Sentinel Prime (voice), played by Jon Hamm.
Starscream (voice), played by Steve Buscemi.
Transformers One is a 2024 American animated science fiction
action film based on Hasbro's Transformers toy line.
It was directed by Josh Cooley from a screenplay by Eric Pearson, Andrew Barrer and
Gabriel Ferrari, the latter two of whom also conceived the film's story.
The film features the voices of Chris Hemsworth, Brian Tyree Henry, Scarlett Johansson,
Keegan-Michael Key, Steve Buscemi, Laurence Fishburne, and Jon Hamm.
It is set on Cybertron, the home planet of the Transformers, and depicts the
origins and early relationship of Optimus Prime and Megatron.
In March 2015, following the release of Transformers: Age of Extinction (2014), Paramount Pictures tasked
Akiva Goldsman to set up a writers' room to create ideas for potential future Transformers films.
By May 2015, Barrer and Ferrari had signed on as writers, and they came
up with the idea of an animated prequel set on Cybertron.
The film was announced in August 2017, and by April
2020, Cooley had been hired to direct.
Animation services were provided by Industrial Light & Magic, and the design
was primarily influenced by the Generation 1 era and Art Deco.
The score was composed by Brian Tyler.
Transformers One premiered in Sydney, Australia, on September 11, 2024, and was
released by Paramount Pictures in the United States on September 20.
The film received positive reviews from critics, who praised the story, animation,
screenplay, voice performances, action sequences, score, and humor.
However, it underperformed at the box office, grossing only $129.4
million worldwide on a budget of $75–147 million.
The film explores themes of based on toy, giant robot,
aftercreditsstinger, duringcreditsstinger, buddy movie.
The tone is thought_provoking.